Chris Rock
Chris Rock
Bigger & Blacker
更黑 更暴力
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士先生...
live from the world-famous Apollo Theater...
g迎淼郊~sHarlem^e世名的...
in Harlem, New York.
Apollo≡
Are you ready?
浜昧?
Please welcome Mr. Chris Rock!
有Chris Rock!
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组==-- http://hd.cnscg.com/ 仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
--==}城家@SCG字幕M==-- http://hd.cnscg.com/ H供翻g交流使用, 禁止用於商I用途
翻译: Uriana single_single 协调: We 校对: Just Married
翻g: Uriana single_single f{: We 校: Just Married
What's up...
~s的各位...
New York?
大家好
There's Brooklyn in the house.
有Brooklyns淼
Well, l'm from Brooklyn.
我也是Brooklyn人
Shit, look at this. White people are up top tonight.
看啊 今晚白人都躲去橇
You know, I was just in my hotel, a little while ago, on my way here...
我馁e^s...
and I got in the elevator, right?
坐梯Π?
I'm getting in the elevator...
我上了梯...
and these two high-school white boys try to get on with me...
後面x高中的白小子想跟M...
and l just dove off.
我立RW了
I said, "Y'all ain't killing me!"
"你可e想⑽!"
I am scared of young white boys.
我怕了白小子了
If you white and under 21, I am running for the hills.
碰到不M21q的白人 我跑的比l都快
What the hell is wrong with these white kids shooting up the school?
熊孩子成天犯校@案 想啥呢?
They don't even wait till 3:00, either.
也不等放W的
Killing people in the morning. That ain't right.
上n⑷ @可不
The Trench Coat Mafia.
什NL衣黑手h
"No one will play with us."
f "]人跟我玩"
"We have no friends. We're the Trenchcoat Mafia."
"]有朋友 孤的L衣黑手h啊"
Hey, I saw the yearbook pictures. It was six of them.
我看你年b了 明明有六成T
I didn't have six friends in high school.
我高中都]有六朋友
I don't got six friends now.
我F在都]有
Shit, that's three-on-three with a half court.
都可以装鐾嫒打三@球了
What the hell is wrong with these kids?
熊孩子想啥呢?
I got people telling me, "Come on, Chris. Come up to a school. Talk to the kids."
有人跟我f "Chris 去W校跟孩子吧"
I'm like, "Fuck the kids!
我就f "去他丫的!"
"Do you got a vest? Maybe I'll think about it."
"去演v有配防背心? 那我考]考]"
Everybody wants to know what the kids was listening to.
大家都想t解孩子什N
What kind of music was they listening to?
什N歌?
Or what kind of movies was they watching?
看什N影?
Who gives a fuck what they was watching?
l管他看什N啊?
Whatever happened to crazy?
就是一}少年
What happened to crazy? What, you can't be crazy no more?
}少年怎N]人提? F在]有了?
Did we eliminate "crazy" from the dictionary?
]有"}少年"@f法了?
Fuck the records. Fuck the movies. Crazy!
P音飞妒 P影啥事 就是}少年!
When I was a kid, they used to separate the crazy kids from everybody.
我小r候 }少年被为拎出
When I was a kid, the crazy kids went to school in a little-ass bus.
那r候 他都坐小破巴士上W
They had a class at the end of the school...
他的教室在最後面...
and they used to get out of school at 2:30.
牲c半就下n了
Just in case they went crazy...
f一他l起...
they would only hurt other crazy kids.
也只到其他}少年
And we was all safe.
年我很安全
We was all safe. Damn, the world's coming to an end.
年很安全 F在全都y了套
You'll have little white kids saying,
F在有白人小孩f
"I want to go to a black school where it's safe."
"我要跟黑人一W校 比^安全"
That's right, man.
是的 各位
And everybody's talking about gun control, got to get rid of the guns.
大家都f要支管制 都不S拿
Fuck that. I like guns.
去他的 我
You got a gun, you don't have to work out.
有把 就不用健身了
I ain't working out. I ain't jogging.
我不健身 不慢跑
You got pecs, I got Tecs.
你有胸肌 我有武器
Fuck that shit. You don't need no gun control.
去他的 支不需要管制
You know what you need? We need some bullet control.
其吧 子才需要管制
Man, we need to control the bullets, that's right.
子管制 Φ
I think all bullets should cost $5,000.
子一lu五千刀
$5,000 for a bullet. You know why?
一l五千 樯?
'Cause if a bullet costs $5,000, there'd be no more innocent bystanders.
因橐话l五千的 就]有o辜群受了
That'd be it.
就是@
Every time someone gets shot, people will be like, "Damn, he must have did something."
@釉儆腥吮 大家就f "@肯定]趾檬掳"
"Shit, they put $50,000 worth of bullets in his ass."
"⑺用了五f刀的子啊"
People would think before they killed somebody, if a bullet cost $5,000.
@ 词⑷艘惨三思了
"Man, I would blow your fucking head off, if I could afford it."
"要是我有X 我就把你^打爆了"
"I'm gonna get me another job, I'm gonna start saving some money..."
"我@就去打第二份工 等蛄隋X..."
"and you're a dead man."
"你就等死吧"
"You better hope I can't get no bullets on layaway."
"你就祈\子]法按揭吧"
So even if you get shot by a stray bullet...
你要是躺了...
you won't have to go to no doctor to get it taken out.
你都不用t生o你取出
Whoever shot you would take their bullet back.
_的把子要回去的
"I believe you got my property."
"您侵琢宋业呢a哦"
That's right, man.
就是@
See, everybody blames the kids as fucking crazy.
F在大家都R}少年
Everybody wants to be mad at the kids for shooting up the school.
校@案大家都怪孩子
What about the parents? The parents.
家L的任呢? 家L
The parents is really fucked up, man.
家L才操蛋吧
Their damn parents need to go to jail for some of this fucking shit, man.
他的家L都坐牢
Cause everybody knows that crazy-ass kid that went to jail.
只要JR坐牢的}少年的
You go, "Man, he ain't never had a chance."
都f "他也可z啊"
"If you'd known his mama, you'd know he gonna be there."
"你看他@幼 他早晚要M去的"
I was at the club the other night, down at Life, chilling at the club.
有天我在Life夜店 夥蘸茑
I'm chilling with this girl. She was dancing.
旁有姑娘 她在那跳舞
It was about 2:00 a.m. I'm talking to her, and realized she had two kids at home.
大概凌晨牲c 她跟我f她家有孩子
I don't mind the two kids at home, that's all good.
把孩子放家Y我o所^
But I'm like, "What the fuck are you doing in a club..."
但我想 "你TM在夜店致..."
"at 2:00 in the fucking morning on a Wednesday night?"
"@可是L三凌晨牲c"
"What the fuck are you doing here?"
"你在@致锬?"
"Is it your birthday?"
"你今天^生日?"
"Did you get a raise?"
"你加薪了?"
"Well, you got to get the fuck out."
"soo我回去"
"You go. I'm kicking you the fuck out. Yes, bye!"
"快走 我要把你Z出去 拜!"
"Go take care of them kids before they rob me in 10 years."
"好好Ш⒆ 免得十年後他泶蚪傥伊"
You got to get your kid on or your groove on.
生娃不泡吧 泡吧不生娃
You can't get both on at the same time. I'm tired of this shit.
哪有@N不任的 受蛄
And a bunch of girls are like:
F在女人f什N
"You don't need no man to help you raise no child."
"不靠男人 自己能Ш眯『"
Shut the fuck up with the bullshit.
eTM放屁了
Yeah, you can do it without a man but that don't mean it's to be done.
是能 那你也Р缓
Shit, you could drive a car with your feet if you want to.
H 我_能用_把方向P呢
That don't make it a good fucking idea.
但我@N上路
I don't give a fuck. You could be the baddest mama on earth.
就算你是世界上最莸
I don't give a fuck how good you are.
我也不在乎
Ain't nothing you can say more powerful than, "I'm gonna tell your daddy."
再怎右巢贿^一句 "心我告V你爸"
Can't fuck with it.
巢贿^的啊
Can't come close to, "I'm gonna tell your daddy."
力完全比不上 "心我告V你爸"
You can have a gun at the kid's head, "I'll blow your fucking head off."
你拿著小屁孩XTf "心我打爆你^"
- "So what?"  - "I'll tell your daddy."
- "那又怎?"  - "心我告V你爸"
"Okay, okay."
"服了 服了"
Can't fuck with it, man.
巢贿^的
I'm tired of bumping into these girls at the club...
我受蛄 工作日晚上能在夜店...
all late on a fucking weeknight.
碰到@些的
I got a little cousin who got left back in the first grade.
我有表弟一年就跟不上
Left back in the first grade...
一年就跟不上啊...
cause his mama's out getting the groove on.
因樗叟莅
You know how dumb you got to be...
到底得多蠢...
to get left back in the first grade?
才一年都跟不上啊?
- "What's four plus four?"  - "Jell-O."
- "四加四是?"  - "果"
But that ain't his fault. That's the mama's fault.
但@不是他的e 是他的e
That's the mama's fucking fault. That's right.
都是他的e
I'm telling my cousin, "Tina, talk to your fucking kid."
我跟他f "Tina 跟孩子ff啊"
"Talk to him, teach him some shit."
"ffh 教c什N"
"If you said more words to him than,'Mommy be back'..."
"除了一句'R上回' 再fce的..."
"he might know something."
"他不@N蠢"
That's right.
就是@
And it's real easy to tell who kids are gonna be fucked up.
那些要完蛋的孩子也很容易看得出
It don't take no scientist to tell who's gonna have some fucked-up kids.
不需要什N＜矸治龅
If the kid calls his grandmamma "Mommy"...
如果@小孩喊奶奶"咪"...
and his mama "Pam," he's going to jail.
喊他大名 他肯定要M去的
You ain't saving no college money, you saving bail money.
你不是在大WWM 的是保金吧
That money's going to Johnnie Cochran.
X都流M律口袋Y
That's right. If the kid can't read, that's Mama's fault.
要是小孩不J字 那就是的e
That is Mama's fucking fault.
肯定是的e
Now, if the kid can't read cause there ain't no lights in the house...
要是小孩]有艨而不J字...
that's Daddy's fault.
那就是爸爸的e
You got this shit down?
懂了?
See, nobody gives a fuck about Daddy. There's some real daddies out there.
]人感x爸爸 @年^好爸爸是有的
I'm not talking about the guy that fucked you and left.
我不是f那些上完就跑的
Fuck him, okay? I'm talking about the real daddies.
去他丫的 我是f那些好爸爸
There's still some motherfuckers out there that handle their business.
是有些人在M父H的
Motherfuckers wanna act like brothers...
像男人一...
There's some brothers that handle their business.
M到父H的
Cause people don't give a fuck... Nobody gives a fuck about Daddy.
]人P心... ]人在乎父H
Everybody takes Daddy for granted. Just listen to the radio.
]人感x父H 你台放的歌
Everything's "Mama. Dear Mama. Always loved my Mama."
全都是 " H鄣 永h勰"
What's the Daddy song? Papa was a Rollin' Stone.
父H的有什N歌? "L石老爸"
Nobody gives a fuck. Nobody appreciates Daddy.
]人P心啊 ]人感x父H
Now, Mama's got the roughest job. I ain't gonna front.
母H是很辛苦 我]f不苦
But at least people appreciate Mama.
但人都感x母H
Every time Mama do something right, Mama gets a compliment...
母H每次小小的成功 我都F她...
cause women need to hear compliments all the time.
女人就得哄著
Women need food, water, and compliments.
女人嘛 要吃要喝要R屁
That's right.
就是@
And an occasional pair of shoes.
有一p百搭的鞋
That's right. Women got to hear it all the time, or they lose their minds.
女人每天都要好 不然抓狂的
And get Daddy to make sure you thank your mama for everything.
你爸要催你去F你
"Tell your mama how good the food is. Tell her how nice the house looks."
"快跟你f@菜好吃 跟她f房子好乾Q"
"Tell your mama how nice her hair looks."
"跟她f她型很好看"
"Did you tell your mama? You better go in there and tell your mama."
"f了]? 快去f"
That's right! "Tell your mama."
是的! "跟f"
Nobody ever tells Daddy shit.
l也不F爸爸
I'm talking about the real daddies that handle their fucking business.
我是f那些MM的父H
Nobody ever says, "Hey, Daddy, thanks for knocking out this rent."
]人f "爸 xx你付了房租"
"Hey, Daddy, I sure love this hot water."
"爸 @崴澡洗得真舒服"
"Hey, Daddy, this is easy to read with all this light."
"爸 有了 晚上就能看了"
Nobody gives a fuck about Daddy.
]人P心爸爸
I'm talking about a daddy that handles his business. Nobody gives a fuck about Daddy.
我是f那些MM的父H ]人P心
Think about everything that the real daddy does:
想想看父H的
pay the bills, buy the food, put a fucking roof over your head.
交房租 付I菜X o你一家
Everything you could ever ask for.
是他o了你一切
Make your world a better, safer place.
o你一更好更安全的h境
And what does Daddy get for all his work?
父H有什N回竽?
The big piece of chicken. That's all Daddy gets...
大u排而已 回缶褪...
is the big piece of chicken.
一K大u排
That's right. And some women don't want to give up the big piece of chicken.
有些女人B@都不o
"Who the fuck is you..."
"你以樽约菏钦l啊..."
"to keep the big piece of chicken?'
"把大u排藏著掖著?"
"How dare you keep the big piece of chicken!"
"你怎N敢把它藏著!"
A man can't work 12 hours and come home to a wing.
你男人累死累活回家 就啃bu翅算蛋啊
When I was a kid, my mama would lose her mind...
我小r候 要是l不小心...
if one of us ate the big piece of chicken by accident.
把大u排吃了 我抓狂的
"What the fuck! You ate the big piece of chicken?"
"H! 你把那Ku排o吃了?"
"Oh, Lord! No, no."
"天!"
"Now I got to take some chicken and sew it up and shit."
"害得我只好拿c碎u肉拼一起了"
"Get me two wings and a pork chop. Daddy'll never know the difference."
"o我拿u翅一K排骨 反正你爸吃不出"
Just can't do it. Can't do it.
^Σ恍邪 ^Σ恍
I don't know, man. The world's nuts. It's all good for Clinton.
接著f F在真y 不^克林D倒是偷著
Any time something bad happens, it's good for Bill Clinton.
只要出y子了 克林D就偷著
Just gets people off his ass.
]人R他了嘛
"Stop thinking about me. Good. Kids got shot. Good."
"]人管我 好事 和被 好事"
"Good. People are not thinking about me."
"]人想到我"
"Tornadoes. Good."
"ZL 好事"
"People ain't thinking about me."
"]人P注我"
Clinton damn near got impeached, for what?
克林D差c被劾了 因樯?
For what?
因樯?
Lied about a blowjob so his wife wouldn't find out.
不就偷情不想老婆知道嘛
Is that against the law?
@也犯法了?
Do you need the Supreme Court for that one?
@也要最高法院砼?
You could have took that one to The People's Court!
人民法院足矣!
Could have took that one to Judge Judy.
可以上o朱蒂法官判
She'd have knocked it out in a half hour, plus commercials.
算上V告rg 她半小r就湍闩型
What the fuck did Clinton do?
克林D到底犯什Ne了?
They was charging him with shit I didn't even know was crimes.
他指控的那些事哪犯法了
"You got her some gifts." So what he got her gifts? That's his friend.
"你送她Y了" 送了又怎? 他z是朋友
You can't buy your friend a gift?
朋友g不能送Y物?
"Tried to get her a job." You can't get your friend a job?
"土怂找工作" 不能团笥颜夜ぷ?
Shit, 80% of the people in this room got their job...
H 在鲇邪顺捎^的工作...
because a friend recommended them.
都是朋友推]才成的
It's against the law to get your friend a job?
团笥颜夜ぷ鞣阜了?
Shit, she blew him for a couple of months.
我日 她o他吹吹了那N久
The least he could do is give her a recommendation!
他至少也要o封推]信吧!
It's the least he could do.
也就o得了@c回
See, people...
大家...
everybody expects this holy behavior cause he's the President.
所有人都X得y就要特}
Expect him to behave this holy way.
不能被玷污
He's just the President. He ain't Rev. Clinton.
他是y而已 又不是克林D神父
It ain't Pastor Clinton. It ain't Maharajah Clinton.
又不是克林D牧 又不是克林D大王
It is just Bill Clinton. He's just a man. A man's gonna be a man.
就只是比克林D 男人嘛 都有七情六j
A man is basically as faithful as his options.
桃花有多缺 就有多忠\
That's how faithful a man is, no more, no less.
就是@ 不多不少
You see all these fat Republican guys going,
那些共和h的大胖子f
"I would never do such a thing. This is a travesty."
"有人o我吹我也不@ @是原t性e`"
I'm like, "Nobody's trying to blow you."
我心想 "TM有人o你吹"
Ain't no 20-year-old girls trying to blow Orrin Hatch.
哪有20q的姑娘去oOrrin Hatch吹啊(前⒆hT)
Ain't nobody trying to give Newt Gingrich some.
哪有人o牛金F吹啊 (前h院l言人 也爆出性h)
I don't give a fuck, you ain't never gonna hear Newt Gingrich go,
我不管 @子你也不到牛金Ff
"Man, I wish these hoes would back up off me."
"哎 有妹子往我身上"
"I wish they would just back the fuck up off me."
"我真希望她自重c"
Let a player play, shit!
人生苦短 及r行!
That's right.
就是@
It's damn near impossible for a man to turn down sex.
要男人拒^送上T的妹子基本不可能
It's hard for a man to turn down sex.
@事太y了
We can stop chasing it, and even that requires some rehab.
hold住自己不是不行 但@也得^痈脑
But it's hard for a man to stop.
拒^就更ef了
If it chase us, we can't run that fast.
送上T的 我躲不及啊
It's gonna catch us, we're like,
肯定要被推倒的
"Shit, pulled a hamstring. You got me."
"擦 抽筋了 被推了"
You can't run that fast.
躲不及啊
See, it's easy for women to turn down sex. It ain't shit for y'all to turn down sex.
女人很容易就拒^掉了 你一c不在乎
It ain't no thing for y'all to turn down sex.
都是小菜一碟
Y'all like, "Why can't you turn it down? I do it all the time."
你f "你槊拒^不了T惑? 我天天拒^啊"
"Why can't you say no? I say no." See, it's easy for y'all. You know why?
"f不 有那Ny? 我天天f" 你@N淡然 知道樯?
Cause every woman in here, ever since you were 13...
因樵谧的各位女士 13q_始...
every guy you met has been trying to fuck you.
她就天天被男人搭
That's right. Women are offered dick every day.
就是@ 天天有男人I
Every woman in here...
在座的所有女士...
gets offered dick at least three times a week.
每周至少被I三次
Three times a day, shit!
每天三次 H!
That's right, every time a man's being nice to you...
就是@ 每次有男人I@勤...
all he's doing is offering dick. That's all it is.
那就是I 就@N直接
"Can I get that for you? How about some dick?"
"我湍隳冒? 睃c?"
"Could I help you with that? Could I help you to some dick?"
"我湍惆? 湍睃c?"
"Do you need some dick?"
"你需要?"
Nobody offers us shit.
可]人o男人I
We got to fend for ourselves.
我只好自己邮
We can't believe it when we get an offer. We're like, "Damn, this is my lucky day."
有妹子送上T我都@了 "今天哥走狗屎\啊"
That's right, man.
就是@
See, this whole Monica Lewinsky scandal, a lot of this shit is Hillary's fault.
克林D性h 很大一部分是希拉Y的e (克林D夫人)
That's right, I said it.
我就把R@了
I said it. It had to be said. Somebody got to say it.
R@了 要有人f的
Everybody's like, "Hillary's a hero." No, she ain't.
公f "希拉Y是英雄" 她才不是
Aquaman's a hero.
水行b才是 (漫超英雄)
He can talk to the fishes. What the fuck can Hillary do?
他能跟~f 希拉Y有啥技能?
A lot of this shit is Hillary's fault, cause, ladies, you know your man.
很大部分都是希拉Y的e 因榕人都看得透自己男人
You know your man better than he knows himself.
比他自己看得透
You know what kind of man you got.
你知道你男人啥品N
You know if you got the crazy, need-a-blowjob-all-the-time man.
要碰到@N"不被吹死"的男人
So sometimes you gotta save your man from himself.
你就得H自上啊
So you know what happens if he don't get his medicine.
你也知道他j求不M了怎
So Hillary Clinton put us all in danger.
希拉Ys不我好歹
She put the security of the free world in jeopardy...
是她威{了社治安...
and she needs to suffer the consequences for her actions.
她就得榇烁冻龃r
That's right, she's the First Lady.
她是第一夫人啊
She's supposed to be the first one on her knees to suck his dick!
第一夫人就是要第一去跪舔丈夫的人!
Shit!
H!
That's right. Monica Lewinsky shouldn't have even stood a chance.
就是@ 根本都不到R厮够
Hillary's supposed to already be down there like, "Hey, I got it."
希拉Y早跪在那f "我hold得住啊"
"I've got it. I got the dick."
"胚@Y我能搞定"
"Tickle his ass, or something."
"你去菊花吧"
"Yeah, grab a ball, make yourself useful."
"蛋蛋也行 e光站著"
And they always been on Clinton.
克林D被盯著
Before any of this happened, they was on Clinton.
]@事 他也中
What was they on him for?
年是什N事?
Gays in the military. Everybody says, "Don't let them in."
同性佼兵 大伙都叫喊著"基佬不能M啊"
If they wanna fight, let them fight, cause I ain't fighting.
想打仗就他打h 反正我是不去
I wouldn't give a fuck if I saw a Russian tank rolling down Flatbush Avenue.
就算俄人的坦克_到Flatbush大道 我也不管
I ain't shooting nobody. So call me a faggot.
我才不上瞿 叫我基佬h
When the war is over, I'll be the faggot with two legs, thank you.
Y束後 就我@基佬四肢健全 感激不M
You know what's fucked up? Everybody gets so homophobic.
知道啥操蛋N? 大家同性
People, we need to cut that shit out...
T位 早想_c了...
cause everybody in this room got at least a gay cousin.
l家]同性儆H戚啊
Every last one of you got a gay cousin.
l家]有表兄弟是基啊
You knew he was gay when y'all was kids.
小r候你就看得出
You was playing ball, he was jumping rope.
你去打球 他在那跳K
He didn't turn gay, he was gay then. He just didn't have nobody to be gay with.
基是先天的 不是後天的 只不^r]找到心鄣哪腥
Shit, I got a gay uncle. Call him Aunt Tom.
我有基佬叔叔 我喊他Tom姨
Every Christmas, he comes over with his "friend."
每年}Q 他都他男性"朋友"
See, it don't make no sense to hate nobody.
歧是站不住_的
It don't make no sense to be a racist, sexist, or nothing, but... It don't.
不管是N族歧 性e歧 是e的...
It doesn't.
站不住_的
It don't make no sense...
@就是o理取[...
cause whoever you hate will end up in your family.
你歧l 我祝你家多l
That's right, you don't like gays, you're gonna have a gay son.
同性 我就祝你鹤痈慊
You don't like Puerto Ricans?
波多黎各人?
Your daughter's gonna come home with "Livin' la vida loca!"
我祝你女赫@拥 "狂人生啊!"
Don't you just love that shit?
@歌不好?
That's a catchy-ass song.
@真是神曲啊
You just want to jump up on shit. "Livin' la vida loca!
到就u[有]有 "狂人生啊!"
"Come on!"
"一起!"
I feel that shit. I'll be driving, "Livin' la vida loca!"
多Ц 我一_一唱 "狂人生啊!"
I love that shit.
我鬯肋@神曲了
That ain't going nowhere. That's gonna be out a long time.
N音@ 三日不^啊
That shit is like the Puerto Rican Whoomp! (There It Is)!
@歌就好像波多黎各的"最炫民族L"!
I was talking about my gay uncle.
我f到基佬叔叔
See, your uncles prepare you for life.
叔叔是你人生第一n
If you got enough uncles, they'll prepare you for life...
你叔叔要蚨嗟脑 就是人生百B啊...
cause you got every type of uncle.
什N叔叔都有
You got your gay uncle, you got your alcoholic uncle.
有基佬叔 酗酒叔
You got your stealing uncle.
小偷叔
You got your molester uncle.
猥叔
Everybody's got that one molester uncle.
l都有@N猥大叔
Your mama's like, "Where them kids at?"
你 "孩子去哪了?"
- "They're with Johnny."  - "Get them kids!"
- "Johnny叔ё吡"  - "快回!"
"Hurry up, get them kids! Don't leave them with your Uncle Johnny!"
"快 回! e等Johnny叔λ下毒手啊!"
Later on, you get molested, your mama get mad at you.
Y果你被猥C之後 你R你
"That's what you get."
"你@是"
"Hanging around fucking Johnny. I told you about that shit!
"跑去跟Johnny玩 早警告你了!"
"Now walk it off!"
"L去散散心!"
That's your family.
@就是你家
I don't know. Let's talk about Clinton.
咱回到克林D上面
One thing Clinton did I didn't like, raise taxes. Taxes all high and shit.
克林D唯一一件我不爽的事 加 太高了
You know what's fucked-up about taxes?
有多操蛋?
You don't even pay taxes. They take tax.
不是主尤ソ 是直接被扣啊
You get your check, money gone.
拿到工Y X早]了
That ain't a payment, that's a jack.
交 不如f被交
Got all these taxes: city tax, state tax, Social Security tax.
也太多了 市州社保障
You don't get the money until you're 65.
65q才_始返福利
Meanwhile, the average black man dies at 54.
要知道 黑人平均勖才54啊
Shit, we should get Social Security at 29!
H 29q就o我l社保金了!
What the fuck, man? We don't live that long.
搞毛? 我活不了那N久
Hypertension, high blood pressure, NYPD, something will get you.
健康 高血 ~s警察 有一逮住咱
What the fuck is up with the police? My God!
警察搞毛啊? 天!
I am scared. I didn't get rid of no guns. Fuck that shit.
我怕死了 我必要持 去他的
And I had a cop pull me over the other day, scared me so bad...
某天一警察把我逼停了 o我得...
made me think I stole my own car.
我以槲业能真是偷淼
"Get out the car, get out the fucking car! You stole this car!"
"下 快TM下! @是你偷的!"
I'm like, "Damn, maybe I did."
我心想 "H 真的O"
"Oh, Lord, I done stole a car."
"哦天 我偷了"
You know what's worse than taxes? What's worse than tax is insurance.
比更操蛋的是什N? 是保U
You got to have some insurance.
要Ic保U
They shouldn't even call it insurance. They just should call it "in case shit."
乾脆e叫保U了 叫"就怕f一"
I give a company some money in case shit happens.
我交了cX 就怕f一出事
Now, if shit don't happen, shouldn't I get my money back?
如果不出事 你是不是把X退o我?
That's right, man, you better have some medical insurance, or you gonna die.
就是@ 各位 ]有t保U 就等死吧
That's right, everybody. You got to eat right and exercise.
就是@ 健康食m度都是屁
No, you don't, you need some coverage.
只要I保U就行了
Coverage will save your life.
保U才能救你一命
That's right, we all gonna die, but at least if you got some coverage...
人都有一死 但如果你I了保U...
you will die on a mattress.
你至少能死在床上
That's right. When I was a kid, we didn't have no insurance.
我小r候 家Y]I保U
We didn't have a damn thing.
啥也]有
You had to be damn near dead to see the doctor.
快死了才能去看t生
You had to be way past Robitussin.
要到惠菲治不了的地步 (一N止咳)
That's all we had when I was a kid: Robitussin.
小r候家Y就只有惠菲
No matter what you got, Robitussin better handle it.
不管你得什N病 最好惠菲有用
- "Daddy, I got asthma."  - "Robitussin."
- "爸 我哮喘"  - "砩谆莘"
- "I got cancer."  - "Robitussin."
- "我癌Y了"  - "砩谆莘"
I broke my leg, Daddy poured Robitussin on it.
腿骨折了 我爸把惠菲倒在腿上
"Yeah, boy, let that 'tussin get in there.
"好了鹤 它慢慢BM去"
"Yeah, boy, let that 'tussin get on down to the bone.
"好了鹤 等它B到骨^Y"
"The 'tussin ought to straighten out the bone. It's good.
"@能把骨^捋直了"
"If you run out of 'tussin, put some water in the jar, shake it up, more 'tussin.
"惠菲要]了 就往瓶子Y倒c水 u一u 又有了"
"More 'tussin!"
"MM一瓶!"
Y'all like doctors 'cause they don't cure shit.
你都坩t生 他啥也不用治
They don't cure nothing.
屁都治不好
Same diseases been hanging out since I was a kid, man.
@N多年^去了 治不好的病是治不好
What's the last shit a doctor cured? Polio.
最近攻克的病是什N? 小郝楸
You know how long ago polio was?
小郝楸远级嗑们暗氖铝?
That's like the first season of Lucy.
那都是的事情了
Shit, Fred had an Afro with finger waves!
H 那r的我抱著破木吉他啊!
Have you ever met anybody with polio?
F在有l得小郝楸缘?
Anybody feel a little 'poly around you?
你l小r候麻痹了?
No. That's right, they don't cure shit.
所以 他根本就]治啥
The same diseases been hanging out since I was a kid:
@N多年 治不好的病依f治不好
AlDS, sickle cell, tuberculosis, cancer, Jerry's kids still limping around.
艾滋 罴胞血 肺Y核 癌Y Jerry在障和
I've been watching the Jerry Lewis Telethon...
我看Jerry Lewis助目...
for probably about 15 or 16 years now.
有十五六年了吧
Not one stitch of progress whatsoever.
毫oM展
Come on, man. Lie to me, Jerry!
oc力 __大家也好啊 Jerry!
What the fuck you doing, Jerry?
你致锬 Jerry?
Put a stick in the kid's back, prop him up or some shit!
往背上埋根棍子啊 把他纹!
Come on, call Steven Spielberg.
把Spielberg喊(阿凡_а)
Get some special effects on this shit!
o他做特效!
Get George Lucas on the case!
把George Lucs找! (星球大а)
CGI, motherfucker!
用算C模M啊!
What the fuck!
搞毛呢!
Tie some string around him, make a cripple puppet or some shit.
o他栓赘 做木偶影
Lie to me!
_大家也好!
Where the fuck's the money going?
X都去哪了?
What, to keep Jerry's hair black?
怎N 都被他拿去染了?
Where's the money going? Think about it.
X去哪了? 大家想想
Frank Sinatra: dead. Dean Martin: dead. Sammy Davis: dead.
和他一年代的音芳都x我而去了
Jerry Lewis got a full head of black hair.
只有他一^黑
And if you ain't gonna cure the disease, cut the kids a check!
要是你治不好 就拿Xa孩子啊!
That's right, you know the little boy who's getting ready to die? Get him a table dance.
那快要死掉的小男孩? o他管舞
Get him a table dance, for Christ's sake!
o他管舞 老天啊!
I'm sure the Make-A-Wish people hear that request every now and then.
@N望可多了去了
Get the boy a table dance.
o他管舞
"What do you want, Jimmy? You're dying. Wanna meet Jim Carrey?"
"你有什N望 Jimmy? 你快死了 想金P瑞?" (好R]喜√焱)
"No, I want some big titties in my face."
"不 我死在大波妹的胸Y吧"
"It's my last wish, come on."
"拜 @可是我的z啊"
That's right, man.
就是@
That's right, we got AlDS out there. You think they're gonna cure AIDS?
F在有艾滋病 他能治好艾滋?
No, they can't even cure athlete's foot.
] B香港_都治不好
They ain't curing AIDS. Shit, they ain't never curing AIDS.
艾滋肯定治不好 永h都治不好
Don't even think about that shit.
想都e想
They ain't curing it, cause there ain't no money in the cure.
他不o你治好 治好了就]X拿了
The money's in the medicine. That's how you get paid, on the comeback.
_才有X 病人}\ XLL
That's how a drug dealer makes his money, on the comeback.
和毒一性| 都是提成的
That's all the government is:
政府也是如此
a bunch of motherfucking drug dealers, on the comeback.
政客就一拓毒的 一每油Q一迷倏
They ain't curing no AlDS.
艾滋肯定治不好
That's all it is.
f白了就是@
You think they're gonna cure AIDS?
你X得他攻克艾滋?
They're still mad at all the money they lost on polio!
他在庑郝楸]浦X呢!
Curing AIDS? Shit, that's like Cadillac making a car that lasts for 50 years.
攻克艾滋? @不是P迪拉克去造能_50年的嘛
And you know they can do it...
明知他做得到...
but they ain't gonna do nothing that fucking dumb.
他才不做@N傻事呢
Shit, they got metal on the space shuttle that can go around the moon...
他用在航天wC上的材料@著月球...
and withstand temperatures of up to 20,000 degrees.
忍受高_扇f度的高
You mean to tell me you don't think they can make an Eldorado...
你TM敢告V我 他造不出...
where the fucking bumper don't fall off?
保U杠不自己掉的Eldorado?
They can, but they won't.
明明能造他不造
So what they will do with AIDS is the same thing they do with everything else.
Ω栋滋也@
They will figure out a way for you to live with it.
他找到一N把病一
They don't cure shit, they just patch it up.
治瞬恢伪
Get you to the next stop, so they can get more of your money.
你活得越久 他榨的X越多
They ain't gonna cure it.
^Σ把病治好的
Hopefully, in our lifetime, you're gonna see somebody go:
希望在有生之年 能有@N一番鼍
"Yo, man, you weren't at work yesterday. What's up?"
"嘿 你昨天怎N]上班?"
"My AIDS is acting up.
"我艾滋病犯了"
"You know, when the weather get like this, my AIDS just pop up."
"唉 @天一 我@艾滋病又_始折v了"
"But I took some Robitussin. I'm fine now!"
"但只要弄c惠菲 啥都好了!"
That's right, man. AIDS is scary, man.
就是@影∮H 艾滋病可人了
I took my AIDS test, passed it, got 65.
我去查了艾滋病 ^了 65分哦
You know what's scary about the AIDS test?
知道@y哪Y人不?
What's scary is you don't get the results back for five days.
人在yY果要等五天才出
Five days, that's a long time.
五天啊H @等得
And you know what happens in those five days? You start reflecting.
知道@五天Yl生什N? 你天天反省
You start thinking about every nasty, skank-ass...
你_始回每一次做得不乾不Q...
questionable piece of sex you ever had...
疑c重重的...
and everybody got a few.
@人人都有份
And you're like, "God, what the fuck was I thinking?"
你就 "我擦 我TM怎N想的啊?"
"1993. She didn't even have teeth!"
"1993年 她牙]L全啊!"
"Oh, God!"
"我去啊!"
"What the fuck was on my mind?"
"我TM怎N想的?"
It's like the movie Scrooge, and the Ghost of Pussy Past comes.
跟人鬼情未了一影 ]之不去的影在眼前h啊
"Remember me? I'm Itchy, the stripper from Miami."
"得我? 我是逼W啊 ~阿密跳衣舞的"
You know what else happens after you take an AIDS test?
知道你做了zy之後致锊?
You start calling up people to see if they're alive.
你_始o那些人挨打 看看她活著不
- Hello, can I speak to Lisa?  - This is Lisa.
- 你好 Lisa在?  - 我是Lisa
- Hello, can I speak to Tammy?  - Tammy dead.
- 你好 Tammy在?  - Tammy去世了
"What happened?"
"l生什N了?"
"She got hit by a bus."
"她被公交撞了"
"Thank the Lord! Yes!"
"x天x地! 太棒了!"
"Go Greyhound!"
"我的小心K啊!"
"Yeah, she got hit by a bus!"
"太棒了 她被公交撞死了!"
"Livin' la vida loca!"
"狂的生活啊!"
At least they're still working on AIDS. At least they're trying to get rid of AIDS.
好歹他在研究艾滋病 研究怎N治K@病
Some diseases, they just gave up on.
有些病呢 人家都放了
There's some diseases, if you get them, you on your own.
@些病啊 你要得了 你就自求多福吧
They ain't gonna have no telethon for you...
媒w也不聿ツ...
R. Kelly ain't singing no song.
]有R. Kellyo你唱歌搞慈善募捐
You just got this shit, that's right.
就@病陪著你
You get paralyzed, they don't got shit for you.
你要c了 ]人拍懔
Look at Christopher Reeve, paralyzed.
看看Christopher Reeve(影"超人"演T) c了
Superman can't walk. What kind of sorry-ass shit is that?
超人不走路了啊 @TM多叫人心碎啊?
Superman can't walk. What's next? What the fuck!
超人坐椅 下回是啥? 搞毛啊!
Aquaman gonna drown in the tub?
水行b盆浴溺水?
What the fuck kind of injustice is this?
@算哪T子道理?
Superman can't walk.
尼超人不走路了
The Hulk gonna get the gout? What the fuck!
G巨人得痛L了? 搞毛啊!
Now you go tell a doctor you paralyzed, they don't got shit for you.
你F在要c了去看t生 人家什N都o不了你
"Doc, I'm paralyzed. What you got?"
"t生我c了 怎Nk?"
"Why don't you take this chair and roll your ass around town?"
"要不你就坐椅在外面DD吧?"
"Is that all the fuck you got is a goddamn chair?"
"你TMo得出手的就是一椅?"
"Where do I take this prescription, to a furniture store, motherfucker?"
"我拿著@方找l去啊 找u砭愕?"
"I gotta go to IKEA? What the fuck is this shit?"
"是不是得去宜家啊? @TM是搞毛啊?"
"I said I can't walk. I didn't say I can't sit!"
"我f我走不了 不是我坐不了!"
That's right. And if you go blind, they don't got shit for you.
就是@ 你要是瞎了 你也只能自求多福
Look at Stevie Wonder, been blind for 40-something years...
看看Stevie Wonder 一瞎40多年...(美歌手 出生不久即失明)
got all the money in the world. Don't know if he got hundreds or ones!
足了世界上的X s不知道手上是一K是一百K的!
It's just a stack to Stevie.
Stevie碚f也就是一摞X
They don't got... Stevie can't see shit.
他才不管... Stevie看不啊
Can't see the day, the night, the shadow, the shade, can't even get a peek!
看不白天 看不晚上 看不到影 看不到u 瞄一眼都不行!
Just a peek. Can we help Stevie get a peek? Get a fucking peek!
就瞄一眼啊 能不能Stevie瞄一眼啊? 就TM瞄一眼啊!
The man wrote Songs in the Key of Life, Talking Book, Innervisions.
他了@N多L石sI排名前100的唱片
Can we get this brother a peek? Just a fucking peek!
能不能瓦@哥好橐谎? 就瞄一下啊!
Is that asking for too much? Just a... That's it.
@要求很高? 就... 就@影
You tell the doctor you're blind, he don't got shit for you.
你要跟t生f你看不了 他]H的
"Doc, I'm blind. What you got?"
"t生 我失明了 怎Nk呢?"
"Why don't you take this dog and have the dog drag your blind ass around town?"
"要不你就恐@狗 它е你在城YD吧?"
"That's all the fuck you got, is a damn dog? Man, if I could see, I would whup your ass!"
"你就@c了 一l破狗? 我f要是我]瞎 我扇死你丫的!"
"A fucking dog! What the fuck is wrong with you?"
"一l破狗! 你@是搞毛?"
"Come on, give me a midget or something!"
"拜啊 o我弄侏儒什N的啊!"
That's right, blind people should get midgets.
就是@ 盲人配侏儒
All blind people should get midgets.
所有的盲人都配侏儒
It's hard enough living life when you're blind.
瞎了^日子已虿俚暗牧
Now they gotta learn how to talk dog.
F在得W怎N和狗f
What kind of shit is that? You can't see, so you can't read the dog's lips.
@TM算什N事情? 你又看不 ]法x狗的唇Z
You just listen.
你只能
"What, my shoelace untied? What?"
"啥 我鞋]M好? 你f什N?"
"Is it cold outside? What?"
"外面有c冷? 啥啊?"
"Is somebody at the door? What, motherfucker?"
"T口有人? 草泥Rf什N啊?"
Just give blind people midgets.
就o盲人配侏儒
And if you're a midget, it's already hard enough to get a job.
而且σ侏儒碚f 找工作本砭屠洗箅y了
Just have the midget tell the blind man where to go. Be a seeing-eye man.
叫侏儒o盲人指路就是了 做盲人的眼睛
Just walk in front of the blind man like, "Yo, man, you gotta make a left."
就走在盲人前面 然後f "唷 往左拐一哈"
"Just make a left, brother."
"哥 往左拐哈"
Racism everywhere, everybody pissed off. Black people yelling, "Racism."
到都是N族主x l都不爽 黑人嚷嚷 "N族主x"
White people yelling, "Reverse racism."
白人嚷嚷 "黑人N族主x"
Chinese people yelling, "Sideways racism!"
中人嚷嚷 "道路N族主x!"
And the Indians ain't yelling shit 'cause they dead.
印第安人什N都嚷嚷不出 因樗都炝
So everybody bitch about how bad their people got it.
l都逼逼自己^得多苦逼
Nobody got it worse than the American Indian.
]人比印第安人^得更苦逼了
Everybody need to calm the fuck down.
lTM都o我把嘴]上
Indians got it bad. Indians got it the worst.
印第安人那悲“ 人品|底了
You know how bad the Indians got it? When's the last time you met two Indians?
知道他多K? 你上次同r看到印第安人是啥r候?
You ain't never met two Indians.
你都]C同r看印第安人了
Shit, I have seen a polar bear ride a fucking tricycle in my lifetime.
H 我@子北O熊T小三憾家^
I have never seen an Indian family that's chilling out at Red Lobster.
就是]^有一家子印第安人 在大r餐d吃
Never seen it.
]^
Everybody wanna save the environment. Shit, I see trees every fucking day!
l都在保oh境 尼 湮姨焯炜吹玫桨!
I don't never see no Indians.
就是看不到印第安人
I went to the Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade this year.
今年Macy的年度感恩大[行我去了
They didn't have enough Indians for that shit.
他都不蛴〉诎踩肀硌莅
They had a bunch of Pilgrims.
他雇了一颓褰掏 (⒃v民的人)
When it came time for the Indians, they had three real Indians...
等到了印第安人上龅r候 出F了三真的印第安人...
and the rest was a bunch of Puerto Ricans with feathers in their hair.
剩下的都是X袋上插著羽毛的波多黎哥人
What the fuck! Shit, I know Puerto Ricans when I see them.
搞毛啊@! H 波多黎哥人我一眼就看得出
You can't slip a Puerto Rican by me.
e指望有一能奈已燮さ紫铝镞^去的
That's not Pocahontas, that's Jennifer Lopez!
@不是"L中奇" @是Jennifer Lopez啊!
Racism everywhere. Who's the maddest people? White people.
哪Y都有N族主x 但l最狂? 是白人
Not y'all. Y'all all right.
]f你哈 你好得很
You paid money to see me, we cool.
掏了腰包砜次 o可挑剔
The feud is over.
一笑泯恩仇
No, you watch the TV, watch 60 Minutes. You see white people pissed off, man.
你@一看 看"60分"(美新sI) 你看白人@獾冒
Man, the white man thinks he's losing the country.
告V你 白人X得自己要亡了
You watch the news: "We're losing everything. We're fucking losing."
看@新Yf得: "我什N都要]了 ⊥税"
"Affirmative action, and illegal aliens..."
"平喾ò赴 非法移民啊..."
"and we're fucking losing the country."
"@家都快不是我的了"
Losing? Shut the fuck up. White people ain't losing shit.
⊥? 去你MD ⊥说慕^Σ皇前兹
If y'all losing, who's winning?
你要⊥肆 l在步步I?
It ain't us.
反正不是我黑人
It ain't us. Have you driven around this motherfucker?
不是我黑人啊 你丫有]有_出T看^?
Shit, there ain't a white man in this room that would change places with me.
H 在座的白人 ]有一肯跟我Q的
None of you would change places with me. And I'm rich!
一都]有 而且我很有X哦!
That's how good it is to be white.
做白人就能有@N好
There's a white, one-legged busboy in here right now...
在座某只有一l腿的 在餐^打s的白人...
that won't change places with my black ass.
肯定不成我
He's going, "No, man, I don't wanna switch. I wanna ride this white thing out."
他f "x了哈 我不Q 我是自己摸爬L打吧"
"See where it takes me."
"看能混出什NY果"
That's right, 'cause when you white, the sky's the limit.
就是@影 如果你是白人 前途h在天
When you black, the limit's the sky!
你要是黑人 前途近在眼前!
That's right, man. Now, when it comes to racism...
就是@ F在一f到N族主x...
do you know who the most racist people are for real, the real most racist people?
知道最N族主x的人是l l最O端?
Old black men.
老年黑人
You find a brother over 60... I know you white people know an old black man.
你要看到一60q的老黑... 知道你白人都JR@N一
You go, "Willie at the job, he's so nice." Willie hates your guts.
你f "咱挝坏Willie 人可好了" 其他恨你恨得咬牙切X
There's nothing more racist than an old black man. You know why?
找不到比老年黑人更N族主x的人了 知道樯?
'Cause an old black man went through some real racism.
因樗是v^真正的N族歧
He didn't go through that I-can't-get-a-cab shit.
他v的不是"我]嗬坐出租"@N
He was the cab.
他就是出租啊
A white man just jump on his back, "Main Street."
一白人往他背上一跳 就f "上主道"
"Left, nigger!"
"左D 黑鬼!"
"Left, you fucking nigger!"
"左D啊 死的黑鬼!"
You know what's wild about the old black men?
你知道那些老黑人牛逼在哪Y?
An old black man, he ain't gonna let you fuck up his money.
一老黑 人f人鬼f鬼
Whenever an old black man sees an old white man...
一老黑o什Nr候看到白人...
the old black man always kisses the old white man's ass.
@岷谀肯定在往白屁股上N
"How you doing, sir? Pleased to meet you. Whatever I can get you, you let me know."
"先生 你好? 很高d到您 能湍的我都M力去做"
As soon as the white man get out of sight, he's like:
但@白人要一D身 他就:
"Cracker-ass cracker!"
"R勒戈壁的!"(@N似YP的，我就@N翻了啊 捏下 TBD)
"I'll put my foot in the crack of your ass, cracker-ass cracker!"
"我一_踢爆你逼拥 R勒戈壁的!"
"I wish that cracker would've said some shit to me, saltine-assed, motherfucking cracker!"
"@逼怎N不o我爆爆粗口呀 R勒戈壁的!"
"Cracker, kiss my ass, you fucking cracker!"
"舔我菊花去吧 v人!"
The white man come back. "Howdy, sir?"
等白人一回 老黑就 "先生 您好?"
I got an uncle real crazy.
我一叔就特狂
My uncle B., 55 years old, hates the white people, married to a white lady.
我逼叔 55q了 恨白人入骨 然後娶了白人老婆
And he sits around going, "These crackers ain't shit, except for Susie."
他坐那嘴就 "那桶兹硕疾坏煤盟 除了Susie"
He tried to explain the whole thing to me one day.
有天他想把事情的睚去}o我f明白
He said, "Yeah, I got a white wife. I love her, she love me. That's all that matters."
他f "是 我是娶了白人做老婆 但我鬯 她畚 就蛄"
"But I'll tell you this: if the revolution ever come, I'll kill her first..."
"但我跟你f: 哪天黑人要革命了 我上手就把她做了..."
"just to show these crackers I mean business!"
"o那桶兹丝纯蠢献硬皇峭嫱旱!"
"Motherfucker, cracker-ass, motherfucker cracker! Shit, cracker, motherfucker!"
"R勒戈壁的! 天⒌ H!"
"Hey... Hi, honey."
"嘿... 嗨 老婆好"
"Motherfucker cracker. I'll kill my cracker kids, too!"
"R勒戈壁的 我把我那逼孩子也做了 H!"
That's right, man. I don't know, black....
就是@ 嗯 黑人...
What do we need, y'all? I think we need a new leader.
黑人到底需要什N? 我X得我要一新的I袖
We ain't had a black leader in a while. In a long time.
@多久]新的黑人I袖了 很久了吧
Somebody that moves you.
能深深打幽愕
You know, we had Martin Luther King, Malcolm X...
你懂的 R丁・路德・金啦 R科姆・艾克斯啦...(黑人人噙\蛹)
and ever since then, a bunch of substitute teachers.
拇酥後 就那代n老
We ain't had the real thing. I want a motherfucker to move me.
砭]磉^有真砘锏 我要找能真正打游业陌
Who we got? Let me break everybody down. We got Al Sharpton, all right.
我能找cl呢? 我o大家ff啊 有Al Sharpton(黑人牧 人噙\蛹)
Al Sharpton's all right. He ain't Malcolm or Martin...
@不e哈 他]之前那N犀利...
but if you get your ass whupped by the cops, he's the guy to call.
但你要被l子逮了 就找他去吧
Of course, Al kind of looks like Bookman from Good Times...
然 Al有c像"Good Times情景喜"Y那u的...
but don't let that fuck you up.
e以貌取人嘛
Who else we got? Jesse Jackson. Jesse's all right.
咱能找l呢? Jesse Jackson (黑人牧 人嗷蛹) 他也活
Jesse went over there, Jesse got them hostages.
他w^去 人|就放出砹
I don't know how the hell he did that shit.
我都不知道他怎N做到的
He went over there with no money, no sweet potato pie.
他^去不уX 也不Ш贸缘
What the fuck did Jesse say? Jesse must've been, like:
你猜他TM怎Nf得? 他肯定f:
"Do you want the United States to really be mad at you?"
"想叫美政府真的不爽你?"
"Give the hostages to me."
"把人|o我就α"
That's what he said, you know. What else we got? Farrakhan?
他就@Nf的 咱有cl呢? Farrakhan? (伊斯m精神\宇I袖)
Farrakhan got everybody together for the Million Man March and everything.
他一手k起了百f黑人大[行那些
But Farrakhan don't like the Jews, which is bugged.
但Farrakhanq太人 @很焊
I get my hair cut on Dekalb Avenue. I never been in a barbershop...
我一直去Dekalb街上剪^ 但我]在一家理店Y...
and heard a bunch of brothers talking about Jews.
到一秃谌嗽谡fq太人
Black people don't hate Jews. Black people hate white people!
黑人不恨q太人 黑人恨的是白人!
We don't got time to dice white people up into little groups.
我]心思o你做分
"I hate everybody! I don't care if you just got here."
"你白人我l都恨! 管你是砻怎N"
- Hey, I'm Romanian.  - You Romanian cracker!
- 你好啊 我是_R尼淼  - 你_R尼逼拥!
We need a fucking leader, man.
我需要一I袖啊
When we got no leaders, when something happens...
我]I袖的r候 一旦出了什N事...
we make the shit bigger than it is.
我就小}大作
It's big, but don't make it bigger than it is.
不是小事 但e放得太大
I'm watching the news, and like, "Tupac Shakur was assassinated."
我看新 f"Tupac Shakur被\⒘"
"Biggie Smalls, assassinated. Struck down by assassin's bullets."
"Biggie Smalls被暗⒘ 被⑹舻沽"
I'm like, "No, they wasn't!"
我心Y想 "我去你大的!"
Martin Luther King was assassinated.
R丁・路德・金是被暗⒌
Malcolm X was assassinated.
R科姆・艾克斯是被暗⒌
John F. Kennedy was assassinated.
JF肯尼迪是被暗⒌
Them two niggers got shot.
@黑鬼就是被做掉了啊
Shit, I love Tupac, I love Biggie, but school will be open on their birthday.
H 我超Tupac 超Biggie 但他生日W校不停n放假
I don't think you'll see their pictures hanging up...
目y你也不看他的照片...
in your grandmamma's living room.
出F在你奶奶家客dY
"That's Abraham, Martin, and Pac."
"@是林肯 R丁和Tupac"
"And right here, I got one of Jesus and Biggie on the seesaw."
"@Y呢 上帝和Biggie玩EE板的模型"
"Jesus always in the air."
"上帝在上端喔"
We need a leader. You know who I think the black leader should be?
我需要一I袖 我X得哪人最m合呢?
- Who I think the black leader should be?  - Who?
- 我X得l最合m?  - l?
Pat Riley.
Pat Riley嘛 (F~阿密峄痍主席)
Coach Pat Riley.
Riley教 (曾NBA球T及教)
No man has led more black men to the promised land...
再也找不出l 比他ьI^更多黑人...
than Coach Pat Riley.
走向幸福彼岸的了
He may not get us to the mountaintop, but he'll get us to the playoffs.
他倒未必把我上了峰 但上季後妥妥的
And that's all we want.
@泳蛄
We got a lot of women here tonight. Love the women.
今晚在座有很多女士 我喜g女人
You know who my favorite women are? Big, fat, black women.
但知道我最喜g哪N女人? 又延址实暮阪
Give me a sister about 350 pounds.
o我359磅的黑妹
The best people in the whole world. You know why?
她最棒了 知道樯?
'Cause we live in a society where nobody likes who the fuck they are.
F在@社 l都ψ约翰M意
Everybody's on Prozac, or some shit.
l都心理抑d 健康
Everybody's getting cosmetic surgery.
l都去做整容手g
Nobody likes who the fuck they are except fat, black women.
除了又延址实暮阪
Fat, black women don't give a fuck what you think.
她才不管你怎N想呢
She's going out on Friday night.
她L五晚出去嗨就出去嗨
She got an outfit on. That shit match.
衣服一套 居然合身
She got the pumps on, and the pump fat coming out the pump.
高跟鞋一穿 _背上的肥肉都D出
That's right. It looks like they baking bread in her shoe.
]e @鞋就像在烘I包一
"Baby, your foot ready yet? I'll just sprinkle some cinnamon on it."
" 你@_烤好]? 好了我撒c肉桂上去"
That's right. She got an anklet on, and that anklet's holding on for dear life.
Φ 一p黑z 可z的m子都快被D爆了啊
Black women don't give a fuck. She's like, "I'm sexy."
黑妞才不管 "老娘火辣得很"
"I am sexy, yes, I am!"
"老娘就是性感 ]e!"
"I am the sexiest motherfucker here tonight!"
"今晚最性感的就是姐!"
"Yeah, I got a gut. There's some good pussy under this gut!"
"是 我是肚子大 但@堆肉下面藏著好|西!"
That's right. You want some of this so you can "livin' la vida loca!"
就是@ 真w慕@B度 你也能砭 "狂的生活啊!"
Love the women, man. Women, women.
喜g女人啊 女人女人女人
What the fuck do y'all want?
你到底想要什N?
Do you know what you want? Do you know where you're going to?
到底想要什N? 你知道自己要致?
Do you like the things that life is showing you?
喜g你生活中所面Φ囊磺?
Do you know? What the fuck do women want?
你知道? 女人TM到底想要什N?
I know what you want: everything.
我知道答案的: 一切
That's every woman's answer: "Everything." Women want every fucking thing.
每女人都是: "一切" 女人什N都要
Women act like life was just a big sale, or shit.
ε人碚f 生活就像是大甩u一
"I want to get the most shit before things close down."
"PT前 能拿的我都得拿下"
That's what fucking life is to a woman: everything.
生活ε人碚f就是: 得到一切
You know what men want?
知道男人想要什N?
Food, sex, silence. That's it.
o吃 o睡 耳根清Q 就@
Food, sex, silence.
吃 躺倒 安安oo
"Feed me, fuckme, shut the fuck up!"
"o吃 o操 o我]嘴!"
Our goals seem very attainable, don't they?
咱男人的目撕芫唧w Π?
Women, it's hard to figure women out.
女人啊 太y弄懂她了
It's hard being a guy. We always think we can buy sex.
做男人苦啊 我X得XI得到妹子
"If I take her here, she'll give me some. If I buy her this, she'll give me some."
"我要她去那Y 就搞定了 我要o她I@ 就搞定了"
Nothing get you nothing.
屁都I不到我告V你
A woman knows if she's gonna fuck you within the first five minutes of meeting you.
初次面 5分辱b定出沤z是高富
Women know right away.
她一眼看穿
They're shaking hands like, "I'm gonna fuck him."
握手的r候 她就 "@我要了"
"I hope he don't say nothing too stupid."
"希望他管好自己的嘴"
That's right, fellas, don't say nothing too stupid...
]e啊H 千f管好自己的嘴...
because women are all about the mood.
因榕人什N都看心情
If she's in the mood to fuck you, shut up and let it happen.
如果她一心想著把你上了 把嘴]上好好享受
'Cause if you say the wrong thing, them panties are coming up mighty fast.
一旦你fe什N 那妊提上淼乃俣冉^Σ宦
"What'd you say?"
"草泥R你f毛?"
She be on the phone with a girlfriend, "Yeah, I was gonna give him some..."
她跟|蜜打 "是啊 本硐牒煤酶他L床蔚..."
"but he just started talking."
"但@逼_始管不住自己嘴了"
"I hate a yakking man, child."
"最TM┍票七哆兜哪械牧"
That's right, man. Relationships: easy to get into, hard to maintain.
]e啊 坳PS就是搭上容易 Soy
Why are they so hard to maintain? Because it's hard to keep up the lie.
槭颤NPS就那NySo呢? 因榧包不住火啊
'Cause you can't get nobody being you. You got to lie to get somebody.
]人壅的你 你得去忽悠
You can't get nobody looking like you look, acting like you act...
就@L相l也拿不下 你@幼...
sounding like you sound.
你@音
When you meet somebody for the first time, you're not meeting them.
扇顺醮我面 你到的根本不是他真身
You're meeting their representative.
的都是他的代表
That's right. Who are the biggest liars, men or women?
]e l是大忽悠 男人是女人?
- Men!  - Women!
- 男人!  - 女人!
Men lie the most, women tell the biggest lies.
男人忽悠得最l繁 但女人忽悠得最害
Men, we lie all the time. We lie so much, it's damn near a language.
各位 我一天到晚就是忽悠 一句删渲e
It's like, to call a man out for lying...
逮到一男人撒e...
is like playing basketball with a retarded kid and calling him for double dribble.
就像逮一打@球的智障蛇\ @N
You gotta let some shit slide.
有些事一b眼]一b眼
Men, we lie all the time.
男人嘛 我一直在忽悠
You know what a man's lie is like? A man's lie is like, "I was at Tony's house."
男人一般都忽悠些什N呢? 一般就是 "我在Tony家"
"I'm at Kenny's house." That's a man's lie.
"我在Kenny家" 男人一般就忽悠@些事情
A women's lie is like, "It's your baby."
女人忽悠些什N呢 "@是你孩子"
We've all heard that one.
@句咱]少
- It don't even look like me.  - He's got your hat.
- 他L得都不像我啊  - 他的帽子和你的很像哦
That's right. Who the biggest liars? Women the biggest liars.
]e啊 l是大忽悠? 女人是大忽悠
Look at you, all of you.
看看你 你都是
You're a fucking liar. You!
臭不要的_子 你!
You're a liar!
你也是!
You're all liars. All of you are fucking liars!
你都是 都是臭不要的_子!
Masters of the lie, the visual lie.
e言大啊 迷惑大
Look at you. You got on heels, you ain't that tall.
看看你 穿了高跟鞋 你人有@N高
You got on makeup, your face don't look like that.
你化了y 你本黹L@
You got a weave, your hair ain't that long.
你接了^ 你^有@NL
You got a Wonderbra on, your titties ain't that big.
你@胸|得 你咪咪有@N大
Everything about you is a lie, and you expect me to tell the truth?
你@]一邮钦娴 指望我o你f句真?
Fuck you!
去你大的!
Men lie, we live lies. That's why we so crazy.
男人撒e 我活在e言Y啊 所以我才@N狂
Every now and then, we catch ourselves living a lie.
每r每刻 我都lF自己活在e言Y
We create a whole lie-world around us.
我造了一e言的世界
For instance, every man in this room is hiding some porno in his house.
比如 在座的每男的 家Y都藏一些A片
Every man in here got a pornography stash in the crib.
在座所有的男人都有一A片的秘密藏匿c
That's right.
]e
Not an illegal amount, just enough to get you by.
]到`法那N多 但^蚰闼
Thank you.
xx
And when we hide porno, we go all out.
我藏A片的r候 那使出身解蛋
It ain't behind the refrigerator or under the bed.
]人藏冰箱後面 藏床底下
No, we become Batman when it's time to hide some porno.
藏@的r候我身蝙蝠b了哦
That's right, you hit the light switch, the whole bookshelf shifts to the side.
]e 你一拍舻拈_P 整架往上滑_
You go down two flights of stairs into your porno cellar.
你往下走山翘 淼侥愕A片地窖
Janet Jacme, Kobe Tai, Jenna Jameson, that's right.
Janet Jacme啦 Kobe Tai啦 Jenna Jameson啦 ]e
But women always find the porno.
但藏的片是被女人lF
But they don't find it in the porno hiding place. Oh, no.
但聿皇窃诓啬潼c被lF的 喔不
Where do women find the porno at? In the VCR.
女人都是在哪Y找到S碟的? 影碟CY
And fellas are like, "Damn, how can I be so dumb to leave it in the VCR?"
所有男的心Y都想 "H 我怎N@N傻逼把碟留在碟CY了?"
I'll tell you why.
我告V你怎N回事
'Cause when you're jerking off, you ain't in your right state of mind.
因槟隳且话l出淼r候 你X子肯定{屏了
Your brain's all cloudy and foggy. I'll tell you exactly what happened.
你@X子Y啊 一片F 告V你@咋整的
One day, your woman left early.
某天早上 你老婆早早出T上班去了
You had the whole house to yourself.
整家Y 就你一人
So you said, "Let me get a little jerk before work."
你f "嗯 要不上班之前硪话l吧"
So you in the house, getting your jerk on. Nice good jerk, too.
所以呢 你在家 把碟放起 Y面的热葸很正
You know, that ain't-nobody-in-the-house jerk.
你懂的 @N"霸一屋"]
That's a good jerk. It ain't like that somebody-in-the-next-room jerk.
@]起]得f 不像"隔有耳"]
That's a bad jerk. That's like, "Who's that?"
那]得不爽 是"l?"
I don't like that jerk.
隔有耳不行
I'm talking about the good jerk, that nobody-ain't-home jerk.
我f的是]得o力的 霸一屋那N
So you get the Vaseline ready...
你把凡士林浜...
and you just look at your dick and go:
然後你低^看著你老二f:
"Scream if you want to. No one's gonna hear."
"想叫就M情叫吧 ]人得到"
And right then, your relationship's in trouble. That's right.
然後你的婚姻就要危C了 ]e
'Cause if you can't share what you're like, you'll have problems.
因槟喜g的|西不一 就出}
When you love somebody, you got to love everything about them.
你凵夏人的r候 你得鬯的全部
You got to love the crust of a motherfucker.
角角的地方你都得喜g
You can't just love the white part of the bread.
吃I包不能只喜g中g又白又嫩的地方
You gotta love the crust, the crumbs, the tiny crumbs at the bottom of the toaster.
有 I包屑 I包C下每一粒小I包屑都不能漏了
That's what the real motherfucker is.
真正的矍槭沁@拥
Whatever you into, your woman gotta be into, too, and vice versa...
你喜g啥 你女人也得喜g啥 反之亦然...
or the shit ain't gonna work.
不然@日子^不下去
It ain't gonna work.
^不下去}
That's right. If you born-again, your woman gotta be born-again, too.
]e 你要_始信奉上帝了 你女人最好也_始信教
If you a crackhead, your woman gotta be a crackhead, too...
如果你嗑上了 那你女人最好也跟著一起嗑...
or the shit won't work.
不然日子]法^
You can't be like, "I'm going to church, where you going?" "Hit the pipe!"
日子不可能是你f "我去教堂了 你呢?" "我去抽煽!"
That relationship ain't going nowhere.
@NPS]前途的
Two crackheads can stay together forever.
嗑的能^^嗑一子
That's right, what's gonna happen? They're gonna stop fucking, that's right.
如果那 l生什N呢? Φ _始不L床瘟
They'll stop talking, stop fucking.
_始]f ]床L
You ever been in bed with your woman, both talking dirty, and you go too far?
有]有哪次你和妹子在床上翻覆雨 你突然一句把操全撒了?
You ever say some shit that gets you kicked out of bed?
有]有f^什N 她直接一_把你蹬下床了?
And the woman's like, "Fuck me, harder! Fuck me, Daddy, spank me!"
比如那女的叫 "H我 用力啊! 快H我 爹地 打我屁股!"
- All right, you ho.  - Who you calling a ho?
- 好的 你u  - 你管l叫u?
"Who the fuck are you calling a ho?"
"你TMfl是u啊?"
"Untie me!"
"把老娘_!"
I ain't no expert or no shit, but, fellas, if you're gonna talk dirty to your woman...
我不是＜疑兜 但哥 你要跟你女人fv兮兮的...
you got to talk with authority.
f得r候必有威信
You can get a woman to do any nasty little thing you want.
你叫你女人做多下流的事都可以
You say that shit like a man, make a little eye contact...
你只要f得阂稽c 一小眼神...
put a little bass in your voice, she will do that shit.
音磁性c 她言
She wants to do that shit. She's dying to do that shit.
她非常主 她急不可耐的
Your woman is nastier than you ever imagined.
你女人比你能想像的要下流装俦
But you gotta come correct...
但你f的r候得把嘴捋咯...
because anything you mumble ain't getting done.
如果你吱吱唔唔了 你就玩旱叭グ
You can't be in bed all unsure, like, "Excuse me..."
在床上你不能柔寡喟 f什N "抱歉..."
"Excuse me, I was wondering..."
"抱歉啊 我在想..."
"Ma'am, I have a request. Could you lick my balls?"
"女士 我有一求 你能舔下我的蛋?"
"I ain't licking nothing. Lick your own balls!"
"舔你大舔 要舔自己低^舔去!"
See, if you just said it right, you'd been in there.
所以 如果你f好了 你就搞得定
Now you got dry balls.
F在你的蛋就干在那Y了
That's right, confidence always wins.
]e 有自信的永h站上L
Do you realize, it is 1999, some women still don't give head?
知不知道 都1999年了 有女人不接受口活?
Ninety-fucking-nine.
尼九九年了啊
Whenever I meet a girl that doesn't give head...
每次我碰上不肯吹的女的...
I look at them like a damn Betamax, "They still make you?"
我看著她像看著一P磁б "你@型的]停a啊?"
And when it comes to head, there's three types of women:
f到口活 就能分出三女人:
A: Women that don't give head. Bye, leave, see you.
第一N: 不接受口活 拜 走了啊 再
B: Women that give you just enough head to shut you up.
第二N: o你吹紫 好你把嘴]上
You ever meet them women? They're like, "You okay?"
有碰到^@N女人的? 她就@ "怎N?"
I hate them women!
我最@N女的!
And number three, my favorite woman:
第三N 鄙人最:
the woman that likes nothing better than to suck a dick.
@N女的 舔啪褪撬的最
That's right, God bless all of you!
]e 上帝保佑你!
That's right, you make the world a better place to live in.
就是@ 你世界得更美好了
I want you to suck my dick like you think the antidote's in it!
我要你吸我的r候 感XY面有解一!
Like you trying to get some Robitussin out of that motherfucker!
好像Y面吸得出惠菲一!
That's right. Relationships: easy to get into, hard to maintain.
]e 婚姻啊: 搭上容易 Soy
Why are they so hard to maintain? 'Cause at some point you just stop talking.
槭颤N@NySM? 因橥蝗挥幸惶 你都不跟Ψ秸f了
That's right, everybody stops talking after a while.
]e ^了段rgl都不f了
You know how it is. You come home and you start nodding.
你懂的啊 你一回家就_始c^
"Yeah, we cool."
"嗯 挺好挺好"
"I'm gonna get a little something to eat."
"我弄c吃的啊"
Why do you stop talking?
槭颤N不f了呢?
'Cause at some point, you have heard everything this person has to say...
因榈搅四骋惶 那人f的每一句你都^了...
and it makes you sick to your stomach.
你TM都得反胃了
You know what they're gonna say before it even comes out their mouth...
他f出口之前你就知道了...
and you just wanna stab them in the neck with a pencil!
你TM就想拿支UP往他脖子上捅啊!
Your can't take the shit no more!
你忍o可忍了!
And they're like,
比如他f
- Remember that time?  - Yeah, I remember that time!
- 得那r候?  - 是 我得!
- I ever tell you about...  - Yeah, you told me about that time!
- 我有]有跟你f^...  - 是你跟我f^了!
"Stop telling me the same shit over and over again!"
"e尼跟我反反覆覆v一件事了!"
"Why don't you go out and get kidnapped, have some new shit happen to you?"
"能不能睃c新r的 你出T被架什N的?"
That's right. Fellas, you gotta talk.
]e各位 你得不停f
That's women's biggest complaint: "You don't talk."
女人最郾票频木褪: "你不跟我f喏"
"You need to talk, let's talk. You don't talk."
"你得和我ff呀 我聊聊吧 你不f喏"
That's right. Women love to talk.
]e 女人就是喜gf
If they had talking in the Olympics, a man wouldn't stand a chance.
要是W\比f 男\TAx都M不了
Women love to talk, but they don't wanna talk to you.
女人喜gf 但她不喜g跟你f
They wanna talk to their man.
她喜g跟自己男人f
But women don't want you to talk-talk.
但她不是要你fff
Women just want you to listen-listen.
她只要你
All a woman really wants you to do is ask her the correct questions...
ε人 就是她一Φ}...
that will allow her to run her fucking mouth!
把她嘴巴_悠!
You set her up, she'll knock them down.
你一句 她o你f
Fellas, you want your woman to be happy?
各位 想你女人__心心的?
All you got to say is, "How was your day?
你要f的就是 "今天怎N?"
"Honey, how was your day?"
"H鄣 今天^得怎N?"
Know why? 'Cause "How was your day?" is a 45-minute conversation to a woman.
槭颤N? 因橐痪"今天怎N?" 她就能f上45分
And as a man, you don't really gotta talk. You gotta just act like you're talking.
作槟械哪 你也不用f什N 你假b在f就是了
"Get out of here. Go on! I don't believe it."
"嗯哼 我去 接著f! 不吧"
"You don't say! Really? Get out of here!"
"e_我! 真的假的? 我勒去!"
"Go on. I don't believe it. You don't say? Get out of here."
"接著f e我 e胡f? 不可能吧"
"I told you that bitch crazy!"
"跟你f了那女的有病!"
You gotta throw in, "I told you that bitch crazy." You know why?
最後@句"跟你f了那女的有病"必得加上 知道樯?
'Cause every woman's got another woman at her job that she can't stand.
因槊女的 有一她看不眼的女同事
Women, y'all exaggerate everything. You turn it into some Dynasty shit, like:
女人 你最坌☆}大作 事比天大:
"She's trying to destroy me!"
"她@是要Я宋野!"
What the fuck are you talking about? You wrap up bags at J.C. Penney's!
你TMf毛啊? 你丫就一在商店做打包的!
What's she doing, ripping up your paper?
她能怎N 把你的袋撕了?
Fellas, you gotta talk. Women, exact opposite.
哥 多f 女同胞 恰恰相反
Y'all gotta learn when not to talk. That's right.
你要W的就是把嘴]上 ]e
You ever notice how no man comes home straight from work?
你有]有想^ 槭颤N男人不下班直接回家?
No man comes home straight from work.
]一男的下班直接回家的
A man get off work, he got to go somewhere.
男人下了班 他得先去哪晃悠一下
He got to drink something, he got to smoke something...
得去喝杯酒 得去抽根...
he got to watch the game, he got to hang with his boys...
得去看球 去基友...
he got to take a drive.
得__
He got to do something that will mentally prepare him...
他得做c事情 自己的X袋浜...
for all the talking he gonna hear when he get home.
回家那些ZZ叨叨
Ladies, it ain't that you talk too much.
各位女士 不是你f的太多
You just talk too much as soon as we get in the fucking door.
只是一M家T 你就_始辟里啪啦f
Let a man get situated. We don't need to hear everything right away.
你男人{整一下 不要一股X全倒出戆
Soon as you take one step in, "You're not gonna believe this..."
想想你一_跨M家T "f了你e不信..."
Let me get my other foot in the fucking door!
我先把第二b_跨M硇胁恍!
Let me get something to eat! Let me get something to drink!
我先弄c吃的行不行! 我先弄c喝的行不行!
Let me take a shit!
我先拉屎行不行!
Go in the fucking kitchen and get me my big piece of chicken!
你丫去N房 把我的大u排拿硇胁恍!
I'm out of here. Thank you, New York!
我完事毫 xx~s的各位!
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组==-- http://hd.cnscg.com/ 谢谢观赏
--==}城家@SCG字幕M==-- http://hd.cnscg.com/ xx^p
翻译: Uriana single_single 协调: We 校对: Just Married
翻g: Uriana single_single f{: We 校: Just Married